Office of Price Administration
© 2005 University of Connecticut
Office of Price Administration, Hartford Branch Records.
1941-1951
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center.
United States Office of Price Administration, Hartford Branch.
34.5 linear feet.
MSS19790013
The Office of Price Administration, a federal agency, was established in 1941 by Executive Orders 8734 and 8875. During its existence, the OPA was responsible for setting maximum prices on most products. The OPA and several other agencies were consolidated to form the Office of Temporary Controls in December 1946 by Executive Order 9809 and disbanded in 1947. [Additional materials are located in RG 035 at the Connecticut State Library.]
History
The Office of Price Administration (OPA), a federal agency, was established in 1941 by Executive Orders 8734 and 8875. During its existence, the OPA was responsible for setting maximum prices on most products. “Ceilings were also imposed on residential rents. The regulations were gradually modified and extended by OPA administrators—notably Leon Henderson (1941-1942), Prentiss H. Brown (1943), and Chester B. Bowles (1943-1946)—until almost 90% of the retail food prices were frozen.” “Besides controlling prices, the OPA was also empowered to ration scarce consumer goods in wartime. Tires, automobiles, sugar, gasoline, fuel oil, coffee, meats, and processed foods were ultimately rationed.” [Columbia Encyclopedia, Sixth Edition. 2001]
The national office in Washington, D.C., generated the majority of the documents in this collection. Many of the documents were printed pages, leaflets or booklets sent by the main office to the regional branches, one of which was located in Hartford, Connecticut. The regional offices also received teletypes providing interpretations of the price control regulations based on specific cases. The OPA and several other agencies were consolidated to form the Office of Temporary Controls in December 1946 by Executive Order 9809 and disbanded in 1947.
Chester Bowles was the Connecticut State Director for the Office of Price Administration from 1942 to 1943. He also served as the general manager of the OPA in Washington, D.C., from July to October 1943, at which time he was appointed by President Roosevelt to be the price administrator of the OPA. He held the position until February 1946.
Dr. William Harrison Carter, Jr. professor of economics at the University of Connecticut, served as the state price economist for Connecticut (1943-1944) and as a consulting economist from 1944 to 1946. Employed by the University in the Economics (Agricultural) Department since 1931, Dr. Carter was Head of the Economics Department from 1945 until 1954, when he became Dean of the College of Arts and Sciences, a position he held until his retirement in 1966.
Scope and Content
The collection consists of reports, memoranda, published regulations, handbooks, manuals, posters, booklets, and pamphlets generated by the Office of Price Administration during World War II. Additional materials are located in RG 035 at the Connecticut State Library.
Arrangement
Series I: Price Control Reports ( 1943-1947 ) consists primarily of reports and memoranda generated by the Hartford Branch of the OPA. The majority of the reports are brief in nature and tend to be memorandum-like in format. A notable exception is “The History of Milk Pricing in New England” which is considerably longer and more detailed than other reports. Many of the reports are concerned with specific cases of the local OPA office, attempting to resolve disputes concerning the legal maximum prices of goods and services. The series is arranged alphabetically by business type and chronologically therein.
Series II: Price Control Master File ( 1941-1946 ) contains the cumulative set of regulations. [Regulations are also located in Series III, although arranged differently.] There are six types of regulations arranged in four sets of independently numbered sequences: 1. Food Products Regulations (FPRs) 2. Maximum Price Regulations (MPRs), Revised Price Schedules (RPSs), and Supplementary Storage Regulations (SSRs) 3. Supplementary Regulations (SRs) 4. Supplementary Orders (SOs) In addition to the six basic types of regulations, there are revised and temporary versions. For example, the folder labeled “RMPR 129” is listed as an MPR with the notation “Rev.” Each regulation may include one or more of the following: the most recent version, previous versions, teletypes, forms, government booklets, and local memoranda. Those few folders that do not follow this pattern are typically unnumbered and highly specialized in nature.
Series III: Handbooks and Manuals ( 1942-1951 ) contains a set of four handbooks and a set of three manuals that originated within the OPA during and immediately after World War II. In addition to these materials, the series also contains external reports presented to Congressional committees by the OPA, a publications from the Office of War Information on controlling the cost of living, and a folder entitled “General Ceiling Price Regulations” from the Office of Price Stabilization. The handbooks and manuals document the workings of the OPA and, to a lesser extent, one of its successors.
Series IV: Desk Books ( undated ) contains a four column General Desk Book, eighteen volumes of the Commodity Desk Books and an Opinions and Decisions Desk Book consisting of five, non-consecutive volumes. These materials also contain the price regulations. Unlike the items in Series II, which document the development of the individual regulations, these materials provide a “snapshot” if the regulations as updated versions were issued, placed in the books and the superceded materials thrown out.
Series V: Posters and Propaganda ( ca. 1941-1943 ) contains war bond drive material. These materials were not created by the OPA but were used by the OPA in their activities. The series contains numerous posters, pamphlets and empty war bond stamp booklets.
Related Material
Archives & Special Collections has a substantial collection of materials documenting individuals and events taking place in Connecticut during the World War II era. See especially, University Archives, Connecticut Soldiers Collection, Southern New England Telephone Company Records, Cheney Brothers Silk Manufacturing Company Records, E. Ingraham Company Records, Wauregan-Quinebaug Company Records. For detailed information on these collections please contact the curator or ask at the reference desk. For detailed information on these collections please contact the curator or ask at the reference desk.
Index Terms
This record series is indexed under the following controlled access subject terms.
Subjects:
United States. Office of Price Administration.; Price regulation--United States.; Prices--Government policy.; World War, 1939-1945--Economic aspects.
Document Types:
Correspondence.; Notebooks.; Publications.; Administrative Records.; Filers. [printed matter]; Notes.; Identifier.
Restrictions on Access
There are no access restrictions on this collection.
Acquisition Information
The collection was brought to the University by Dr. W. Harrison Carter, Jr., professor of economics and former state price economist (1943-1944) and consulting economist (1944-1946).
Detailed Description
- Series I: Price Control Reports, 1943-1947
  - Bi-Weekly Reports, 1943 April - 1944 February (Box 1:, Folder 1)
  - Cleaners and Laundries, 1943 April - October (Box 1:, Folder 2)
  - Cleaners and Laundries, 1943 November - 1944 March (Box 1:, Folder 3)
  - Dairy Statistics, 1943 May (Box 1:, Folder 4)
  - Food, 1943 July - 1944 May (Box 1:, Folder 5)
  - Frozen Food Lockers, 1943 March - April (Box 1:, Folder 6)
  - History of Milk Pricing, 1942-1946, 1947 January (Box 1:, Folder 7)
  - Ice, 1943 March - August (Box 1:, Folder 8)
  - Letters, 1943 February - March (Box 1:, Folder 9)
  - Milk and Dairy, 1943 February - 1944 August (Box 1:, Folder 10)
  - Other Products and Services, July 1943 - June 1945 (Box 1:, Folder 11)
  - Regional Adjustment Meetings, 1944 February - August (Box 1:, Folder 12)
  - Restaurants, 1944 January - 1945 January (Box 1:, Folder 13)
- Series II: Regulation Master File, 1941-1946
  - Food Produce Regulation
    - 1-5 (Box 2:, Folder 14-24)
  - Maximum Price Regulation/Revised Price Schedule/Supplementary Storage Regulation
    - 1 Restaurant; Eating and Drinking Establishments (2) (Box 2:, Folder 25)
    - 1-1 Eating and Drinking Establishments (Box 2:, Folder 26)
    - 1-2 Eating and Drinking Establishments (Box 2:, Folder 27)
    - 1-3 Eating and Drinking Establishments (Box 2:, Folder 28)
    - 1-4 Eating and Drinking Establishments (Box 2:, Folder 29)
    - 1 Second-hand Machine Tools (3) (Box 2:, Folder 30)
    - 2 Restaurant; Food and Drink (Box 2:, Folder 31)
    - 2 New Restaurant Regulation (Box 2:, Folder 32)
    - 2-1 Eating and Drinking Establishments (Box 2:, Folder 33)
    - 2 Aluminum Scrap & Secondary Aluminum Ingot (Box 2:, Folder 34)
    - 3-1 Eating and Drinking Establishments (Box 2:, Folder 35)
    - 3-2 Restaurant; Eating and Drinking Establishments (Box 2:, Folder 36)
    - 3-3 Restaurant; Eating and Drinking Establishments (Box 2:, Folder 37)
    - 3-4 Restaurant; Eating and Drinking Establishments (Box 2:, Folder 38)
    - 3-5 Restaurant; Eating and Drinking Establishments (Box 2:, Folder 39)
    - 3-6 Restaurant; Eating and Drinking Establishments (Box 2:, Folder 40)
    - 3-7 Restaurant; Eating and Drinking Establishments (Box 2:, Folder 41)
    - 3 Zinc Slab Materials & Secondary Slab Zinc (Box 2:, Folder 42)
    - 4-1 Restaurant; Eating and Drinking Establishments (Box 2:, Folder 43)
    - 4 Iron and Steel Scrap (Box 2:, Folder 44)
    - 5-1 Restaurant; Eating and Drinking Establishments (Box 2:, Folder 45)
    - 5 Temp.; Household Furniture (Box 2:, Folder 46)
    - 6 Iron and Steel (3) (Box 2:, Folder 47)
    - 7-1 Restaurant; Eating and Drinking Establishments (Box 2:, Folder 48)
    - 7 Raw Materials for Cotton Textiles (2) (Box 2:, Folder 49)
    - 8-1 Restaurant (Box 2:, Folder 50)
    - 9-1 Restaurant (Box 2:, Folder 51)
    - 9-2 Restaurant; Eating and Drinking Establishments (Box 2:, Folder 52)
    - 9 Raw Materials for Shoes & Other Leather Products (2) (Box 2:, Folder 53)
    - 10 Pig Iron (2) (Box 2:, Folder 54)
    - 11 Cotton Textiles/Fine Cotton Goods (3) (Box 2:, Folder 55)
    - 12 Brass Mill Scrap (4) (Box 2:, Folder 56)
    - 13 Rev.; Douglas Fir Plywood (2) (Box 2:, Folder 57)
    - 14 Raw Silk and Silk Waste (Box 2:, Folder 58)
    - 15 Copper (2) (Box 2:, Folder 59)
    - 16 Raw Cane Sugars (3) (Box 2:, Folder 60)
    - 17 Pig Tin (2) (Box 2:, Folder 61)
    - 18 Burlap & Burlap Products (Box 2:, Folder 62)
    - 19 Southern Pine lumber (3) (Box 2:, Folder 63)
    - 19A Leg Run Southern Pine Lumber (2) (Box 2:, Folder 64)
    - 20 Temp.; Fresh, Cured, & Canned Meat & Fish (2) (Box 2:, Folder 65)
    - 20 Copper Scrap & Copper Alloy (Box 2:, Folder 66)
    - 21 [no subject heading] (Box 2:, Folder 67)
    - 21 Formaldehyde (Box 2:, Folder 68)
    - 22 Temp.; Fluid Milk & Cream (Box 2:, Folder 69)
    - 22 Pennsylvania Grade Crude Oil (Box 2:, Folder 70)
    - 23 Temp.; Shelled Peanuts, Peanut Butter (Box 2:, Folder 71)
    - 23 Rayon Grey Goods (Box 2:, Folder 72)
    - 24 Animal Hair (Box 2:, Folder 73)
    - 25 Temp.; Corn (Box 2:, Folder 74)
    - 25 Fats, Oils & Their Products (Box 2:, Folder 75)
    - 26 Temp.; Onion Sets (Box 2:, Folder 76)
    - 26 Rev.; Softwood Lumber (Box 3:, Folder 77)
    - 27 Temp.; Broom Corn (Box 3:, Folder 78)
    - 27 Anthracite (Box 3:, Folder 79)
    - 27 Retail Food Price Survey (Box 3:, Folder 80)
    - 28 Temp.; Unprocessed Agricultural Commodities (Box 3:, Folder 81)
    - 28 Solvents (2) (Box 3:, Folder 82)
    - 29 Temp.; Unprocessed Agricultural Commodities (Box 3:, Folder 83)
    - 29 Coke (2) (Box 3:, Folder 84)
    - 30 Wastepaper (2) (Box 3:, Folder 85)
    - 31 Temp.; Rubber and Products (Box 3:, Folder 86)
    - 31 Acetic (Box 3:, Folder 87)
    - 32 Paperboard (2) (Box 3:, Folder 88)
    - 32 Paperboard Sold East of Rocky Mountains (Box 3:, Folder 89)
    - 33 Temp.; Oats, Barley and Grain Sorghums (Box 3:, Folder 90)
    - 33 Raw Materials for Cotton Textiles (Box 3:, Folder 91)
    - 34 Temp.; Sweet Potatoes (2) (Box 3:, Folder 92)
    - 34 Wood Alcohol (Box 3:, Folder 93)
    - 35 Temp.; Tobacco (Box 3:, Folder 94)
    - 35 Carded Grey & Colored Yarn Cotton Goods (Box 3:, Folder 95)
    - 36 Temp.; Gum Resin (Box 3:, Folder 96)
    - 36 Acetone (Box 3:, Folder 97)
    - 37 Butyl Alcohol & Esters Thereof (2) (Box 3:, Folder 98)
    - 38 Glycerin (Box 3:, Folder 99)
    - 39 Woven Decorative Fabrics (2) (Box 3:, Folder 100)
    - 40 Builders' Hardware and Insect Screen Cloth (2) (Box 3:, Folder 101)
    - 41 Steel Castings & Railroad Specialties (2) (Box 3:, Folder 102)
    - 42 Paraffin Wax (Box 3:, Folder 103)
    - 43 Used Steel Drums, Pails & Containers (2) (Box 3:, Folder 104)
    - 44 Douglas Fir Doors (Box 3:, Folder 105)
    - 45 Building Materials (2) (Box 3:, Folder 106)
    - 46 Iron & Steel (2) (Box 3:, Folder 107)
    - 47 Old Rags (2) (Box 3:, Folder 108)
    - 48 Emergency Civil Defense Materials and Equipment (Box 3:, Folder 109)
    - 49 Iron & Steel (2) (Box 3:, Folder 110)
    - 50 Green Coffee (2) (Box 3:, Folder 111)
    - 51 Cocoa Beans and Cocoa Products (Box 3:, Folder 112)
    - 51 Sole Leather Scrap (Box 3:, Folder 113)
    - 52 Pepper (2) (Box 3:, Folder 114)
    - 53 Fats & Oils (4) (Box 3:, Folder 115)
    - 54 Douglas Fir Peeler Logs (Box 3:, Folder 116)
    - 55 Second-hand Bags (2) (Box 3:, Folder 117)
    - 56 Reclaimed Rubber (Box 3:, Folder 118)
    - 57 Wood Floor Coverings (Box 3:, Folder 119)
    - 58 Wool & Wool Tops & Yarns (2) (Box 3:, Folder 120)
    - 59 Kapok (Box 3:, Folder 121)
    - 60 Sugar (2) (Box 3:, Folder 122)
    - 61 [no subject heading] (Box 3:, Folder 123)
    - 62 Cigarettes (2) (Box 3:, Folder 124)
    - 63 Rubber Tires & Tubes (2) (Box 3:, Folder 125)
    - 64 Domestic Cooking & Heating Stoves (2) (Box 3:, Folder 126)
    - 65 Floor Coverings (2) (Box 3:, Folder 127)
    - 66 Rubber and Products (Box 3:, Folder 128)
    - 67 New Machine Tools (2) (Box 3:, Folder 129)
    - 68 Chemicals (2) (Box 3:, Folder 130)
    - 69 Primary Lead (Box 3:, Folder 131)
    - 70 Lead (2) (Box 3:, Folder 132)
    - 71 Cadmium (Box 3:, Folder 133)
    - [72 does not exist]
    - 73 Feeding stuffs (2) (Box 3:, Folder 134)
    - 74 Animal Product Feeding stuffs (2) (Box 3:, Folder 135)
    - 75 Magnesite (2) (Box 3:, Folder 136)
    - 76 Hide Glue (2) (Box 3:, Folder 137)
    - 77 Coke (2) (Box 3:, Folder 138)
    - 78 Oxalic Acid (Box 3:, Folder 139)
    - 79 Solvents (Box 3:, Folder 140)
    - 80 Lithopone (2) (Box 3:, Folder 141)
    - 81 Zinc (Box 3:, Folder 142)
    - 82 Wire & Cable (2) (Box 3:, Folder 143)
    - 83 Radio Receivers & Phonographs (2) (Box 4:, Folder 144)
    - 84 Radio Receivers & Phonograph Parts (2) (Box 4:, Folder 145)
    - 85 New Passenger Automobiles (2) (Box 4:, Folder 146)
    - 86 Domestic Washing & Ironing Machines (Box 4:, Folder 147)
    - 87 Scrap Rubber (2) (Box 4:, Folder 148)
    - 88 Fuel Oil, Gas & Liquefied Petroleum Gas (2) (Box 4:, Folder 149)
    - 89 Bed Linens (2) (Box 4:, Folder 150)
    - 90 Rayon Waste (Box 4:, Folder 151)
    - 91 Tea (Box 4:, Folder 152)
    - 92 Soy Bean & Peanut Oils (Box 4:, Folder 153)
    - 93 Mercury (Box 4:, Folder 154)
    - 94 Western Pine & Associated Species of Lumber [includes revisions] (2) (Box 4:, Folder 155)
    - 95 Women's Nylon Hosiery (2) (Box 4:, Folder 156)
    - 96 Containers (2) (Box 4:, Folder 157)
    - 97 Southern Hardwood Lumber (3) (Box 4:, Folder 158)
    - 98 Titanium Pigments (Box 4:, Folder 159)
    - 99 Chemicals (Box 4:, Folder 160)
    - 100 Iron & Steel (2) (Box 4:, Folder 161)
    - 101 Citric Acid (2) (Box 4:, Folder 162)
    - 102 Mechanical Refrigerators (2) (Box 4:, Folder 163)
    - 103 Salicylic Acid (Box 4:, Folder 164)
    - 104 Vitamin “C” [sic] (Box 4:, Folder 165)
    - 105 Gears, Pinions, Sprockets, & Speed Reducers (Box 4:, Folder 166)
    - 106 Domestic Shorn Wool (Box 4:, Folder 167)
    - 107 Used Tires & Tubes (2) (Box 4:, Folder 168)
    - 108 Fertilizers (Box 4:, Folder 169)
    - 109 Rev.; Aircraft Lumber (Box 4:, Folder 170)
    - 110 Mechanical Refrigerators (2) (Box 4:, Folder 171)
    - 111 Vacuum Cleaners (2) (Box 4:, Folder 172)
    - 112 Pennsylvania Antracite (2) [sic] (Box 4:, Folder 173)
    - 113 Metal Ores (2) (Box 4:, Folder 174)
    - 114 Wood Pulp (2) (Box 4:, Folder 175)
    - 115 Silk Waste (Box 4:, Folder 176)
    - 116 Chine & Pottery (2) (Box 4:, Folder 177)
    - 117 Wooden Containers (2) (Box 4:, Folder 178)
    - 118 Cotton Products (4) (Box 4:, Folder 179)
    - 119 Original Equipment - Tires & Tubes (Box 4:, Folder 180)
    - 120 Fuel (4) (Box 4:, Folder 181)
    - 121 Miscellaneous Solid Fuels (Box 4:, Folder 182)
    - 122 Fuel (3) (Box 4:, Folder 183)
    - 123 Wool (2) (Box 4:, Folder 184)
    - 124 Rolled Zinc Products (Box 4:, Folder 185)
    - 125 Rev.; Nonferrous Castings (2) (Box 4:, Folder 186)
    - 126 Fluorspar (Box 4:, Folder 187)
    - 127 Finished Piece Goods (2) (Box 4:, Folder 188)
    - 128 Processing Piece Goods (2) (Box 4:, Folder 189)
    - 129 Rev.; Paper Products (2) (Box 4:, Folder 190)
    - 130 Rev.; Paper Products (2) (Box 4:, Folder 191)
    - 131 Rev.; Rubber & Products (2) (Box 5:, Folder 192)
    - 132 Rubber Footwear (2) (Box 5:, Folder 193)
    - 133 Farm Equipment (2) (Box 5:, Folder 194)
    - 134 Construction & Road Maintenance Equipment (2) (Box 5:, Folder 195)
    - 135 Fertilizers (2) (Box 5:, Folder 196)
    - 136 Machines, Parts & Industrial Equipment (6) (Box 5:, Folder 197)
    - 137 Rev.; Fuel (3) (Box 5:, Folder 198)
    - 138 Rev.; Ferro-alloys (2) (Box 5:, Folder 199)
    - 139 Used Household Mechanical Refrigerators (2) (Box 5:, Folder 200)
    - 140 Sanitary Napkins (2) (Box 5:, Folder 201)
    - 141 Raw Materials for Shoes (2) (Box 5:, Folder 202)
    - 142 Seasonal Commodities (Box 5:, Folder 203)
    - 143 New Rubber Tires & Tubes (2) (Box 5:, Folder 204)
    - 144 Agricultural Insecticides (Box 5:, Folder 205)
    - 145 Pickled Sheepskins (2) (Box 5:, Folder 206)
    - 146 Hardwood Lumber (Box 5:, Folder 207)
    - 147 Rev.; Bolts, Nuts, Screws & Rivets (2) (Box 5:, Folder 208)
    - 148 Dressed Hogs & Wholesale Pork Cuts (2) (Box 5:, Folder 209)
    - 149 Mechanical Rubber Goods (2) (Box 5:, Folder 210)
    - 150 Finished Rice & Rice Milling By-products (2) (Box 5:, Folder 211)
    - 151 New Bags (2) (Box 5:, Folder 212)
    - 152 Canned Vegetables (2) (Box 5:, Folder 213)
    - 153 Apparel (2) (Box 5:, Folder 214)
    - 154 Ice (2) (Box 5:, Folder 215)
    - 155 Hardwood Lumber (2) (Box 5:, Folder 216)
    - 156 Canned Meat (2) (Box 5:, Folder 217)
    - 157 Sales and Fabrication Textiles (2) (Box 5:, Folder 218)
    - 158 Bicycles & Bicycle Equipment (2) (Box 5:, Folder 219)
    - 159 Rev.; Iron & Steel (2) (Box 5:, Folder 220)
    - 160 Seasonal Wooden Containers (Box 5:, Folder 221)
    - 161 Rev.; West Coast Logs (2) (Box 5:, Folder 222)
    - 162 Office & Store Machines (2) (Box 5:, Folder 223)
    - 163 Wool (2) (Box 5:, Folder 224)
    - 164 Softwood Lumber (2) (Box 5:, Folder 225)
    - 165 Services (7) (Box 6:, Folder 226)
    - 165 Rev.; Services (2) (Box 6:, Folder 227)
    - 166 Zinc Oxides (Box 6:, Folder 228)
    - 167 Rayon Yarn & Staple Fiber (2) (Box 6:, Folder 229)
    - 168 Converted Yarn (2) (Box 6:, Folder 230)
    - 169 Rev.; Beef & Veal Carcasses (5) (Box 6:, Folder 231)
    - 170 Solvents (2) (Box 6:, Folder 232)
    - 171 Rev.; Film Scrap (2) (Box 6:, Folder 233)
    - 172 Apparel (2) (Box 6:, Folder 234)
    - 173 Rev.; Wheat Mill Feeds (2) (Box 6:, Folder 235)
    - 174 Machinery & Transportation Equipment (Box 6:, Folder 236)
    - 175 Glass & Glass Containers (Box 6:, Folder 237)
    - 176 Hardwood Lumber (2) (Box 6:, Folder 238)
    - 177 Men's & Boy's Tailored Clothing (2) (Box 6:, Folder 239)
    - 178 Women's Fur Garments (2) (Box 6:, Folder 240)
    - 179 Pine Oil (2) (Box 6:, Folder 241)
    - 180 Color Pigments (Box 6:, Folder 242)
    - 181 Condensed Soups (2) (Box 6:, Folder 243)
    - 182 Kraft Wrapping Paper (Box 6:, Folder 244)
    - 183 Puerto Rico (4) (Box 6:, Folder 245)
    - 184 Sales by Canners of Maine Sardines (2) (Box 6:, Folder 246)
    - 185 Canned Fruits & Canned Berries (2) (Box 6:, Folder 247)
    - 186 Wooden Containers (2) (Box 6:, Folder 248)
    - 187 Paperboard Products (2) (Box 6:, Folder 249)
    - 188 Various Orders (11) (Box 6:, Folder 250)
    - 189 Bituminous Coal (2) (Box 7:, Folder 251)
    - 190 Free Cotton Linters (Box 7:, Folder 252)
    - 191 Cotton Linters & Hull Fibers (2) (Box 7:, Folder 253)
    - 192 Imported Tar Acids (2) (Box 7:, Folder 254)
    - 193 Domestic Distilled Spirits (2) (Box 7:, Folder 255)
    - 194 Alaska (2) (Box 7:, Folder 256)
    - 195 Industrial Wooded Boxes (2) (Box 7:, Folder 257)
    - 196 Hardwood Lumber Products (2) (Box 7:, Folder 258)
    - 197 Canned & Preserved Fruit (2) (Box 7:, Folder 259)
    - 198 Silver (2) (Box 7:, Folder 260)
    - 199 Lead Bullet Rod (Box 7:, Folder 261)
    - 200 Rubber Heels & Soles (2) (Box 7:, Folder 262)
    - 201 Virgin Islands (Box 7:, Folder 263)
    - 202 Copper (2) (Box 7:, Folder 264)
    - 203 Vitamin “A” (2) (Box 7:, Folder 265)
    - 204 Special Sales of Industrial Materials (2) (Box 7:, Folder 266)
    - 205 Fertilizer Raw Materials (2) (Box 7:, Folder 267)
    - 206 Vitrified Clay Sewer Pipe (2) (Box 7:, Folder 268)
    - 207 Frozen Fruits, Berries & Vegetables (2) (Box 7:, Folder 269)
    - 208 Maximum Prices for Staple Clothing (2) (Box 7:, Folder 270)
    - 209 California Sardines (Box 7:, Folder 271)
    - 210 Fall & Winter Seasonal Commodities (2) (Box 7:, Folder 272)
    - 211 Cotton Ginning Service (2) (Box 7:, Folder 273)
    - 212 Canned & Preserved Foods (Box 7:, Folder 274)
    - 213 Household Furniture (2) (Box 7:, Folder 275)
    - 214 High Alloy Castings (Box 7:, Folder 276)
    - 215 Sales of Softwood Lumber (2) (Box 7:, Folder 277)
    - 216 Eastern Railroad Ties (2) (Box 7:, Folder 278)
    - 217 Hardwood Lumber (2) (Box 7:, Folder 279)
    - 218 Primary Forest Products (2) (Box 7:, Folder 280)
    - 219 Softwood Lumber (2) (Box 7:, Folder 281)
    - 220 Certain Rubber Commodities (2) (Box 7:, Folder 282)
    - 221 Apparel (2) (Box 7:, Folder 283)
    - 222 Softwood Lumber (2) (Box 7:, Folder 284)
    - 223 Hardwood Lumber (2) (Box 7:, Folder 285)
    - 224 Cement (2) (Box 7:, Folder 286)
    - 225 Paper & Products (2) (Box 7:, Folder 287)
    - 226 Jams & Jellies (2) (Box 7:, Folder 288)
    - 227 Dried Fruits (Box 7:, Folder 289)
    - 228 Flue-cured Tobacco (Box 7:, Folder 290)
    - 229 Rubber & Products (2) (Box 7:, Folder 291)
    - 230 Iron & Steel (2) (Box 7:, Folder 292)
    - 231 Raw Spices & Spice Seeds (2) (Box 7:, Folder 293)
    - 232 Apple Butter (Box 7:, Folder 294)
    - 233 Canned & Preserved Foods (2) (Box 7:, Folder 295)
    - 234 Approved Stirrup Pumps (Box 7:, Folder 296)
    - 235 Iron & Steel Foundry Products (2) (Box 7:, Folder 297)
    - 236 Building Materials (Box 7:, Folder 298)
    - 237 Food Products (3) (Box 7:, Folder 299)
    - 238 Food Products (2) (Box 7:, Folder 300)
    - 239 Lamb & Mutton Carcasses (2) (Box 7:, Folder 301)
    - 240 Phosphate Rock (Box 7:, Folder 302)
    - 241 Malleable Iron Castings (2) (Box 7:, Folder 303)
    - 242 Dried Prunes & Raisins (2) (Box 7:, Folder 304)
    - 243 Food Products (Box 7:, Folder 305)
    - 244 Gray Iron Castings (2) (Box 7:, Folder 306)
    - 245 Shellac (Box 7:, Folder 307)
    - 246 Farm Equipment (2) (Box 7:, Folder 308)
    - 247 Domestic Canned Crab Meat (Box 7:, Folder 309)